

Anton Karpushko

iOS developer, 4+ years of experience



An iOS developer experienced in developing a cloud storage app for a service with an audience of 23 million monthly users, creating a mobile SDK from scratch for the top-3 business messenger worldwide by the number of users, and working on a forex broker platform with more than 2 million traders. I am committed not only to writing clean and maintainable code, fully covered by tests, but also to enhancing project metrics related to features I'm working on.



Skills

App modularization, Auto Layout, CocoaPods, Combine, Core Animation, DRY, Figma, Firebase, GCD, git, GitFlow, Keychain, KISS, MVC, MVVM, Objective-C, OOP, Realm, RxSwift, SnapKit, SOLID, SPM, Storyboard, Swift, SwiftGen, SwiftLint, SwiftUI, Tuist, UDF, UI testing, UIKit, unit testing, XcodeGen, XCTest.



Employment

VK / iOS Engineer (Cloud – AppStore top-3 cloud storage app in its domestic May 2022 – Dec 2023 region, Mail.ru - AppStore top-1 email client superapp in its domestic region).

- Reduced time-to-market by 30% for new features related to file viewing by implementing a new file viewer module in Cloud app. Made the module remotely configurable and reusable for other teams.
- Decreased the number of user billing profile loading failures by 83% through refactoring billing profile handling logic and rewriting it from Objective-C to Swift in Cloud. Increased the domain code test coverage by 96%.
- Designed and developed a cross-app feature that allows users to open email attachments from the email client superapp inside the cloud storage app.
- · Regularly participated in the company's internal tech talks as a speaker. Presented "Switching from RxSwift to Combine in a project" and "Swift compiler performance" tech talks.

JivoChat / iOS Engineer (top-3 business messenger worldwide by the Aug 2020 - May 2022 number of users).

- Developed a mobile SDK from scratch for audience of 200K+ clients.
- Implemented 3 APIs for the SDK Swift, Objective-C, and JavaScript (ReactNative); supported 6 major iOS versions; supported all the future Xcode versions by adding module stability support for the SDK binary.
- Wrote complete documentation of **55K+ characters** for the SDK.
- Was directly communicating with 15 clients' development teams at once, solving the SDK integration issues, collecting feedback, and improving the product based on that.

Appricot / iOS Developer (app for a forex broker platform with more than Aug 2019 - Aug 2020 2 million traders).

- · Increased user proof of identity/residence completion rate by 13% through implementation of a new identity and residence verification flow.
- · Rate of user conversion to funded account holders was increased by 14% with implementation of demo account creation flow.
- Increased users onboarding completion rate by 11% after implementing a new onboarding flow.
- Developed country/region-specific features. As an example, added RTL UI direction support for the whole app.



Education

Volgograd State Technical University.

Sep 2016 - Jul 2020

- Bachelor's degree in Applied Computer Science.
- · Graduated with honors.
- Graduation project: a mobile app that helps to prepare for the post-school Unified State Exam.